(神楽)おい寝ぼけてんじゃねえぞ｡
こちとら根っからのｼﾃｨｰ派ね｡
(神楽)こんな田舎もんたちと
一緒にすんなよ｡
Oi, stop daydreaming!
Don't compare me to these country bumpkins.
I was born and raised a city girl.
(阿伏兎)まいったね こりゃ｡
You got me.
I thought you might be, but...
もしやとは思ったが➡
that umbrella, that skin.
その傘 その肌｡
ようやく じいさんとの戦争
避けたと思ったら このｻﾞﾏだ｡
Just when I thought I had stopped the war with the old man, I get this.
勘弁してくれよ｡
Give me a break.
I don't like killing my own kind.
ｵﾚは共食いは趣味じゃねえんだ｡
これも夜兎の血の宿命かね｡
Maybe this is also the destiny of those with Yato blood,
死ぬまで戦い続ける
呪われた種族の｡
to continue fighting until you die.
The cursed clan.
銀ちゃん ここは私に任せるある｡
Gin-chan, leave this to me.
行くよろし｡
(銀時)ﾊﾞｶか｡
You can go.
Are you stupid? He'll be tough even with three people.
３人がかりでも やべえ相手だ｡
(新八)行ってください 銀さん｡
Please go, Gin-san.
神楽ちゃんは ﾎﾞｸが護ります｡
I... will protect Kagura-chan.
は？ 何言ってるあるか！
What are you talking about?
You'll just get in the way.  Just go!
お前なんか足手まといある｡
さっさと行けよ！
You're in the way, Gin-san. Get out of here.
足手まといです 銀さん
さっさと行ってください！
I'm talking about you!
ｵﾒｴだっつ～の！
ったく ｵﾒｴら 待ち合わせの場所は
わかってんだろうな？ おい｡
Jeez.
You two. You know where to meet up, right?
Oi.
次 会うときは｡
陽の下で｡
Next time we meet...
it'll be under the Sun.
上等だ｡
Sounds good.
["Life I A Series Of Choices"]
(阿伏兎)人生ってのは重要な
選択肢の連続なんていうがね➡
Life is...
said to be made of a string of important decisions.
こんだけ はっきり
ﾊﾞﾊﾞ引いたﾔﾂは初めて見たね｡
This is the first time I've seen someone clearly pull the Joker.
あちらさん ﾊｽﾞﾚだ｡
That guy loses.
夜王相手に１人➡
Up against the Night King by himself,
この世に
一片の肉片すら残るまいよ｡
there won't be a single trace of him left in this world.
お前さんたちが正解｡
You two win.
助かったねぇ｡
You're saved...
２人仲よく ﾐﾝﾁにしてやるよ｡
I'll turn you both into mince meat.
(神楽)ﾊｽﾞﾚは お前ある｡
The loser is you.
We're going to turn you into Arabiki wieners!
その粗末なもん｡
(２人)粗挽きｳｲﾝﾅｰにしてやるよ！
Do it!
(百華)やれ～！
(百華)なぜ反撃しない？
Why don't you fight back?
なぜ黙って撃たれるままでいる？
Why do you just stand there taking it?
(月詠)わっちに
ぬしらを殺す権利はない｡
I don't have the right to kill you.
Until now...
今まで わっちは吉原を護るため➡
to protect Yoshiwara...
ぬしらとともに
掟を犯す者たちを裁いてきた｡
together, we judged those who broke the laws.
At times, women who tried to escape from Yoshiwara.
ときに吉原から
逃げ出そうとする女たちを➡
At times, women who were no longer able to attract customers.
ときに
客のとれなくなった女たちを｡
そんな所業を重ねてきた
わっちが➡
I have piled up those burdens.
掟に背きながら己だけ
のうのうと生き残れるとは➡
I can't just abandon these laws and continue to live on peacefully.
思っておらん｡
Kill me.
殺すがいい わっちを｡
But I will buy some time.
だが時間は稼がせてもらう｡
You would turn your back on your own and protect the intruders?!
己が身を呈して
族を護るというのか！
《月詠:この街に
護る価値などありんせん｡
There is no worth in protecting this town.
そう思いながらも
鳳仙の傀儡になり➡
While believing so,
I became Housen's puppet.
I protected Yoshiwara and its laws.
吉原を 掟を護ってきた｡
I couldn't change anything.
何も変えられぬ
何も変わらぬと あきらめ➡
I gave up, believing nothing would change.
日輪のいる この街を護ることが➡
By protecting the town she was in, I was protecting Hinowa herself.
日輪を護ることにつながる｡
そう思って剣をふるってきた》
Believing that,
I've been wielding my sword.
I was not... protecting anything.
わっちは
何も護ってなどいなかった｡
わっちが護ってきたのは➡
What I was protecting...
日輪でも この街でもない｡
was neither Hinowa nor this town.
自分の檻｡
It was my own cage.
ｶﾞﾊｯ…｡
吉原に檻を張ったのは誰でもない｡
A cage was placed around Yoshiwara by none other than ourselves.
わっちらじゃ｡
Fearing Housen and unable to change a thing, we silently watched.
鳳仙を恐れるあまり➡
変わることも
変えることもせずに➡
すべてを諦観し
己が心に檻を張ったのじゃ｡
We placed a cage around our hearts.
己の身のかわいさゆえに
檻に閉じこもり➡
Trapped in a cage because of our own beauty,
we desperately tried to protect that cage.
その檻を
必死に護っておったのじゃ｡
To protect Yoshiwara, to protect Hinowa.
吉原を護る 日輪を護る➡
They were all excuses.
すべては言い訳｡
In order to hide my cowardice, I used Hinowa.
わっちは 己の臆病さを隠すために
日輪を利用したんじゃ｡
何にも変わっちゃいなかった｡
Nothing has changed.
((日輪:ﾎﾝﾄの不自由ってのはね➡
True enslavement...
自分で
心に檻を張っちまうことさ))
is when you place a cage around your own heart.
I haven't changed at all since then.
(月詠)わっちは あの頃から
何も変わっちゃおらんかった｡
((日輪:死ぬだ何だ わめいて
逃げ回ってる暇があったら➡
If you have the energy to whine about dying or whatnot,
檻の中で戦いな！ ﾃﾒｴと))
then fight from within your cage...
against yourself.
日輪 わっちはもう逃げん｡
Hinowa,
I won't run anymore.
檻を破るために戦う｡
I'll fight to break the cage.
((背筋しゃんと のばして
お天道様まっすぐ見て➡
Stand up straight,
watch the heavens,
生きてかにゃならねんだ))
and continue to live your life.
Until the very end,
最後の最後まで…
太陽に向かって➡
facing the Sun,
まっすぐに立ち続ける！
I will stand tall.
(百華たち)やれ！
Do it!
♪♪～
もうできない…｡
もう ｲﾔだ｡
I can't do it anymore.
I don't want to!
頭… ｱﾝﾀは臆病者なんかじゃない｡
Boss,
you aren't a coward.
ｱﾝﾀは 何も
護っていなくなんかない｡
You weren't protecting nothing.
You were protecting something,
護ってくれたじゃないか
私たちを…｡
us.
吉原から逃げ出そうとした女たち
客の とれなくなった女たち｡
The women who tried to escape from Yoshiwara...
The women who no longer attracted customers...
掟を犯した者たちを
始末したように見せかけ➡
The one making it look like those who broke the laws were taken care of,
百華に紛れ込ませ
かくまってくれたのは➡
and sheltered us inside the Hyakka...
他でもない ｱﾝﾀだ｡
was none other than you!
わっちは ぬしらが
女として生きる道を奪った｡
I...
stole the path of a woman from you.
女としての ぬしらを殺してきた｡
I've killed the woman in you.
ここに売られたときに
すでに女などは捨てています｡
By the time we were sold here, we have already forgotten how to be women.
物としてではなく
人として生きる道を➡
Instead of remaining mere objects,
you made the path for us to live as human beings.
作ってくれたのは あなたです｡
ここにいる者たちは皆➡
The ones that are here now,
あなたが今まで
護ってきたものなんです｡
are the ones that you have been protecting.
頭… 空に輝くのは
太陽だけではありません｡
Boss,
the Sun is not the only thing shining in the sky.
太陽も月も この常夜の街を照らす
かけがえのない➡
The Sun and the Moon...
are both irreplaceable lights that illuminate this town of darkness!
光なんですよ！
♪♪～
頭！
Boss?!
《太陽と月…｡
The Sun and the Moon...
わっちは ずっと隣でぬしを
護り続けていたつもりだったが➡
I thought I was by your side protecting you this entire time,
ぬしの存在は どこか遠かった｡
yet you were so far away...
今 はじめて
ぬしの隣に立てた気がする｡
Now, for the first time,
I feel like I was able to stand beside you.
道は照らしたぞ｡
The way has been lit.
吉原を… 日輪と晴太を頼む…》
Yoshiwara...
Hinowa and Seita...
I leave them to you.
(新八/神楽)おぉ～!!
♪♪～
ﾌｯ どうした｡
What's wrong?
The Arabiki wieners aren't ready yet?
あらびきｳｲﾝﾅｰは
まだできんのか？
《歯が立たない
あの神楽ちゃんでさえ➡
I'm no match for him!
Even Kagura-chan is being brushed aside.
軽く あしらわれている
同じ夜兎でも➡
Even though they're both Yato, for there to be such a gap in ability...
これだけ実力差があるなんて…》
ｵﾚたちは 義理や金でも動かねえ｡
We don't act on obligation or money.
夜兎が動くとき それは➡
A Yato only acts...
when there's a battlefield that drips with the stench of blood.
そこに血の匂い煙る
戦場があるときだけだ｡
なんて言われてたのは昔の話でね｡
...Is how it was long ago,
なんてことはねえ こっちゃ
ﾋﾞｼﾞﾈｽで ここ来てるだけだ｡
but not anymore.
I'm just here on business,
が そちらさんは
ﾋﾞｼﾞﾈｽってわけじゃなさそうだな｡
but it doesn't seem like that's your case.
まさか あのｶﾞｷ助けるために？
Could it be to save that little kid?
(神楽)どこあるか？
Where is he?
神威は… ﾊﾞｶ兄貴は
どこにいるって聞いてんだよ｡
I'm asking you where my stupid brother, Kamui, is!
兄貴？ まさか…｡
Brother? It couldn't be...
待て～！ ついに 見つけたぞ!!
Stop!
We finally found him. Surround him quickly!
早く回りこめ！
あと あと少し…｡
Just... just a little furth-
(神威)こんな所で 何してるの？
What're you doing in a place like this?
(神威)ひょっとして
おかあさんでも捜してるのかい？
Are you possibly looking for your mother?
ｱﾘ？ どうしたの？
寒いの？ 大丈夫？
Huh? What's wrong?
Are you cold?
Are you okay?
ねぇ そんなに会いたいなら
ｵﾚに ついておいでよ｡
Hey. If you want to meet her that badly, come with me.
会わせてあげるよ 日輪に｡
I'll let you meet her.
With Hinowa.
(晴太)お おちょくってんのかよ！
A-Are you messing with me?
ｱﾝﾀ ｵｲﾗたちの味方じゃない
鳳仙の味方でもない｡
You aren't on our side.
You're not on Housen's side either.
いったい… 何なんだ｡
Who are you?
あいにく吉原にも
ﾋﾞｼﾞﾈｽにも興味はないんだ｡
Unfortunately, I have interest in neither Yoshiwara nor business.
♪♪～
会いたくなった｡
I want to meet her...
(神威)あの夜王 鳳仙を
腑抜けになるまで➡
The woman who turned Night King Housen into a coward.
たらしこんだ女に…｡
(晴太)うわぁ～!!
(神威)会いたくなった｡
I want to meet her...
吉原じゅうの女たちから
太陽と呼ばれ➡
The woman whom all the women of Yoshiwara depend on as their "Sun".
すがられる女に…｡
(神威)ｵﾚは どうやら➡
Oh dear. It seems like she wasn't one of them.
今まで 捜し人を
間違っていたらしい｡
(神威)
さぁ 会いに行こうか｡
Now, shall we go see her?
吉原で
最も美しく 強い女に…｡
The most beautiful... most powerful woman in all of Yoshiwara.
(阿伏兎)そうか お前さん…｡
I see.
You... now that I think about it... you look like the commander...
(阿伏兎)誰かに似てると思えば
団長の…｡
ｸｯ まいったね こりゃ｡
What to do.
Just when I thought I had coincidentally met a fellow clansman on this remote planet,
こんな遠い星で 偶然にも
同胞に会えたと思ったら…｡
よりにもよって 敵方｡
しかも 仲間の縁者とは｡
she's an enemy.  And to top it off, a comrade's relative.
共食いどころの
騒ぎじゃねえや｡
This goes beyond killing your own kind.
There's no need for concern.
余計な心配いらないね｡
ｱｲﾂは 私のことなんて
なんとも思ってないある｡
He doesn't think anything of me anyway.
同族どころか 家族さえ➡
Forget fellow clansmen, even family.
父親や妹さえ
手にかけようとした 薄情者ね｡
He's a heartless bastard who even fought his own father and younger sister.
そこに部下と
師匠もつけ加えておくといい｡
You can add subordinate and master to that list.
どうやら ｵﾚたちは
似た者同士らしいな｡
It seems we're all in the same boat.
あのﾊﾞｶに振り回されてる
被害者｡
Victims who have been pushed around by that idiot.
兄妹も部下も変わらんな｡
Siblings or subordinates don't matter, huh?
上が ﾁｬﾗﾝﾎﾟﾗﾝだと
下が しっかりするもんだ｡
When the older one is nonchalant, the younger one needs to pick up his slack.
Move aside.
そこをどくある｡
ﾊﾞｶやらかした上 止めんのが➡
Stopping the idiotic actions of the older sibling is the duty of the younger one.
下の役目ある｡
悪いな｡
Sorry.
ﾊﾞｶやらかした上の
尻を拭くのが 下の役目だ｡
Wiping the butts of the higher ups is the duty of the subordinate.
か 神楽ちゃん…｡
K-Kagura-chan...
♪♪～
Take this!
神楽ちゃん!!
Kagura-chan!
(阿伏兎)ﾊﾊﾊﾊ！
T-This is... a fight between Yato...!
《こ これが
夜兎同士の戦い…》
To think that a kid who's never been on a proper battlefield would come after me.
ろくに
戦場に出たこともないｶﾞｷが➡
ｵﾚに 食らいついてくるとはねぇ｡
闘争本能だけは 親父…
いや 兄貴ゆずりというわけか｡
At least your instincts are from your father...
No, they're closer to your brother's.
ｱｲﾂと一緒にするなよ｡
Don't compare me to him.
悪いことは言わねえ｡
お引越しをｵｽｽﾒするぜ｡
I won't belittle you.
I recommend you leave.
こんな ｼｬﾊﾞｲﾔﾂらと
ぬるま湯につかっていたら➡
If you hang around these lame guys too long,
その 一級品の才能 潰れるぜ｡
your first-class potential will be ruined.
なんなら ｵﾚが間に入って
兄妹ｹﾞﾝｶ 仲裁してやろうか？
Or should I get in between and mediate your sibling quarrel?
お前らと一緒にするなと
言ってるある｡
I'm telling you not to compare me to you guys.
夜兎の血に流され
戦場をさまようだけのお前らと➡
You guys are swept away by the blood of the Yato and scour the battlefields.
私は 自分の戦場は
自分で決める｡
I choose my own battlefields.
血ではなく 魂で｡
Not through my blood,
but with my heart.
(神楽)自分の護りたい
もののために 戦場に立つある｡
I stand on the battlefield to protect what I want.
そのｼﾞｬﾏをすると
いうのなら➡
If you're going to get in my way,
同族だろうが 兄貴だろうが
誰だろうが➡
it doesn't matter whether you're my clansmen, my brother, or whoever else...
ぶっ潰すある!!
I'll crush you!
An older brother who fights as his blood commands,
《血の命ずるままに
戦う兄と➡
魂の命ずるままに 戦う妹｡
and a younger sister who fights as her heart commands.
(阿伏兎)いや 血で戦う兄と➡
No, it's more like an older brother who follows his blood and a younger sister who fights against it.
血と戦う妹と
言ったほうがいいのかね｡
どうやら 和解など
ﾊﾅから ﾑﾘな話だったようだな｡
It seems an understanding was impossible from the start.
だが 残念ながら
お前さん➡
However...
Unfortunately, no matter how much you try, you won't beat your stupid brother like that.
そんなことでは
一生かかっても➡
あのﾊﾞｶ兄貴には
勝てやしねえ》
うぉぉぉ～っ!!
なっ…!?
(阿伏兎)さて 問題だ！
And now, a question for you.
倒す拳と 殺す拳…➡
A fist that defeats and a fist that kills...
いったい どちらが重いかな？
Which one is heavier?
(阿伏兎)正解は…➡
The answer is...
殺す蹴りだ!!
a kick that kills!
腕力よりも 脚力のほうが
はるかに強いからな～｡
Destructive power is stronger than brute strength by far.
えぇ～？ 詐欺だって？
What? A trick question?
かたいこと 言うなよ｡
たかが ｸｲｽﾞじゃねえか｡
Don't be so stiff.
It was just a quiz.
(阿伏兎)気づかんかね？
Didn't you notice?
お前さん 無意識のうちに➡
Subconsciously, you pulled back on your punch.
拳に 急ﾌﾞﾚｰｷを
かけてしまっていることに…｡
ぎゃぁぁぁ～っ!!
夜兎の本能を➡
Trying to suppress your Yato instincts,
抑えようとするあまり➡
your punch dies before it even reaches me.
拳が ｵﾚに届く前に
死んじまってんだよ～!!
人を 傷つけたくない…
人を 殺したくない…➡
You don't want to hurt people.
You don't want to kill people.
大層 立派な考えだ｡
It's quite the commendable way of thinking.
On this tepid Earth, that is.
この ぬるま湯 地球ではな…｡
うわっ…！
だが…➡
However,
that kind of thinking doesn't work on the battlefield.
戦場では そんなもの通じない｡
On the battlefield,
戦場では
迷った者から 死んでゆく!!
those who hesitate are the first to die.
血を 拒絶する お前と
それを誇る ｵﾚたち！
You, who rejects your blood, and we, who take pride in it,
ﾊﾅから
勝負になんて なりゃしねえ！
weren't even a match from the outset.
♪♪～
神楽ちゃんを…➡
Kagura-chan...
Let go of Kagura-chan!
神楽ちゃんを 離せ～!!
(笑い声)
(阿伏兎)今のは よかったぜ 坊主｡
That was a good one just now, boy.
殺す気 満々だった…｡ だが…｡
You fully intended to kill me.
However,
ぐほっ…!!
残念…｡
too bad.
That one's not there anymore.
(阿伏兎)そっちは
もう ありゃしねえよ！
Shinpachi!
新八～!!
さぁ ここで また 選択肢だ！
Now, another choice.
どちらが 先に死ぬ？ 選べ！
Which one of you wants to die first?
Choose!
やめろ～!! 新八を離すある!!
Stop it!
Let go of Shinpachi!
そんな選択肢は ねえ！
言ったろ？
That's not one of the choices.
I told you,
人生は 重要な選択肢の連続だ！
life is a string of important decisions.
後悔しねえように
ﾍﾞｽﾄな選択肢を 選ぶんだな！
Make sure to pick the best option so you don't regret it.
おま… が…➡
You...
お前が… 死ね!!
Die!
かたいこと 言うなよ…｡
Don't be so stiff!
たかが… ｸｲｽﾞだろう!!
It's just a quiz, right?!
(阿伏兎)…決まりだな｡
I guess it's decided.
Stop it!
やめろ!!
ぐあぁぁ～っ!!
やめろ～!!
Stop it!
ぐはっ!!
や… やめろ～!!
Stop it!!
Stop it!
やめろ!!
ぐあぁぁ～っ!!
Stop it!
やめろ～!!
ぐはっ!!
や… やめろ～!!
Stop it!!
♪♪～
動きが 突然…➡
Her movements suddenly...
何が あった… あの ｶﾞｷ…!?
What happened to that kid?
(咳き込む声)
か… 神楽… ちゃん…!?
K-Kagura... -chan?
♪♪～
鎖が ちぎれたか…｡
So the chains have broken, eh?
(阿伏兎)人を殺めることを
恐れるあまり➡
The chains that subconsciously suppressed her Yato powers,
because of her fear of hurting others...
無意識に 夜兎の能力を
抑え込んでいた鎖が➡
仲間の危機に瀕して
理性とともに 弾け飛んだか！
In response to her friend's peril...
it disappeared along with her sanity.
…ようやく 目を覚ましやがった｡
You've finally awakened.
ｹﾓﾉが～!!
You beast!
Kagura-chan!
神楽ちゃん!!
待っていたぞ！ お前が来るのを!!
I've been waiting for you to appear!
ちょうど 腕一本じゃ➡
I've been thinking that having just one arm wasn't enough of a handicap!
ﾊﾝﾃﾞが足りねえと
思っていたところだ～!!
♪♪～
理性どころか
知性も 吹っ飛んだか!!
Has your intelligence gone with your sanity?
両手をなくせば 攻めも護りも
ままならねえぜ！
If you lose both hands, you won't be able to attack or defend!
(爆発音)
所詮 ｹﾓﾉはｹﾓﾉでも… 子ｳｻｷﾞか｡
In the end, even if a beast is a beast,
are you a little bunny?
ﾌﾌﾌﾌﾌ…｡
おいおい 冗談だろ｡
Oi, oi. You have to be kidding me.
今のは 結構 ﾏｼﾞだったんだぜ｡
I was pretty serious with that last one.
おじさん 傷ついちまうわ｡
You're going to hurt this old man's feelings.
ううっ!!
《圧倒している…
歴戦の夜兎を 神楽ちゃんが…｡
She's overpowering him!
An experienced Yato... Kagura-chan is...
神楽ちゃん… なのか？
Is that...
Kagura-chan? Is that...
あれが… あれが…➡
Is that...
ﾎﾞｸらの知ってる
神楽ちゃんなのか？》
our Kagura-chan?
♪♪～
(阿伏兎)ｸｸｸ…
まいったね こりゃ…｡
You got me...
ｵﾚが解いた鎖に
つながれていたのは➡
It seems that the chains I took off weren't connected to a beast,
ｹﾓﾉなんかじゃなかったらしい｡
ﾊﾞｹﾓﾉだぜ こりゃ｡
this is a monster.
ぐぉっ…｡
…戦場では 迷った者から死ぬと
説教垂れときながら➡
Even though I lectured you that the ones who hesitate die first on the battlefield,
どうやら 迷っていたのは
ｵﾚのほうだったようだ｡
it seems I was the one who was hesitating.
お前さんを見てると 兄貴のﾂﾗが
ちらついてしかたねえ｡
When I look at you...
I can't help but see your brother's face.
殺すがいい｡
本能の命ずるままに…｡
Kill me,
as your instincts command you to.
No matter how much you struggle against your blood, you're no different from your brother.
どれだけ 血に抗ったところで
お前は 結局➡
兄貴と何も変わらねえ｡
お前は 結局…➡
In the end, you're the same as your brother.
兄貴と一緒なんだ｡
血に従って殺せ…
夜兎を誇って殺せ…｡
Obey your blood and kill me.
Embrace the Yato and kill me.
ｵﾚたちの居場所は
戦場しかねえんだ｡
The battlefield is the only place we belong.
戦場で生き残るには
それしかねえんだ｡
It's what you have to do to survive on the battlefield.
それが 死ぬまで戦い続ける
ｹﾓﾉたちの宿命…｡
That is the duty of beasts that fight until they die,
夜兎の宿命よ!!
a Yato's duty!
うぅぅっ…!!
ぐぐっ…!!
うぅぅ…!!
何のﾏﾈだ？
What do you think you're doing?
お前のためじゃない！
銀さんと 約束したんだ！
I'm not doing this for you.
I made a promise... with Gin-san!
神楽ちゃんは ﾎﾞｸが護る！
ﾎﾞｸが 神楽ちゃんを…！
That I would protect Kagura-chan!
I'll... Kagura-chan...!
ﾎﾞｸらが信じる神楽ちゃんを
護るんだ!!
I'll protect the Kagura-chan we trust!
夜兎でも
ｲｶﾚた兄貴の妹でもない！
Not the Yato,
nor the sister of the crazy brother!
ぶっきらぼうで 生意気で
大食らいで…｡
The blunt...
cocky...
gluttonous...
でも とっても優しい女の子！
but very kind girl!
ﾎﾞｸらの 大切な仲間を護るんだっ!!
I'll... protect our precious friend!
お前なんかのために…➡
I won't let Kagura-chan dirty her hands on the likes of you!
神楽ちゃんの手は
汚させはしない!!
目を覚ませ 神楽ちゃん！
ｷﾐの敵は➡
Open your eyes, Kagura-chan!
Your enemy...
ﾎﾞｸらの戦う相手は
こんな ﾁﾝｹなﾔﾂじゃないはずだ！
The one we have to fight isn't this grimy bastard!
神楽ちゃ～ん!!
Kagura-chan!
…つくづく甘ったれた連中だ｡
What a completely naive bunch.
言ったはずだぜ｡
戦場じゃ 殺すのを迷ったﾔﾂから➡
I've told you.
On the battlefield, the ones who hesitate to kill...
死んでいくんだってよ…！
are the first to die.
さて ここでまた 選択肢だ｡
Now then, here's another choice.
鳳仙を殺さずに
鳳仙に殺されるか…｡
To be killed by Housen without being able to kill him...
鳳仙を殺そうとして
鳳仙に殺されるか…｡
or to be killed while trying to kill Housen...
さて どっちを選ぶ？
Now then, which do you choose?
え？ どっちも
結局 殺されるって？
What? Both end in being killed?
Don't be so stiff.
かたいこと言うなよ｡
たかが ｸｲｽﾞだろ？
It's just a quiz.
人生は 重要な選択肢の連続だ｡
Life is made of a string of important decisions.
お前さんたちの 甘い選択肢で
どこまでいけるか➡
You should see how far your naive choices take you.
やってみるがいい｡
お前…！
言っただろ？
You!
I told you...
ｵﾚは…➡
I...
共食いは嫌いなんだ｡
don't like killing my own kind.
In this world, there's no such thing as a never ending night.
The time has come for the morning sun to rise on this town.
With the sunrise, the Night King should...
go to sleep!
["Those Who Stand On Four-Legs Are Beasts, Those Who stand On Two Legs, Guts, and Glory Are Men"]
[Haruta, brought by Kamui, finally stands up in front pf Hinowa.]
[And then, the savage battle between Gintoki and the king of the Night, Hosen, Begins!!]